# **Ethan Holen**

#### COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY CLASS OF 2022, B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

□720-326-5046 | Sethanholen@gmail.com | #6 ethanholen.com | GethanHolen | Gethanholen-563856174

## Summarv 5 4 1

Current research assistant, and undergraduate at Colorado State University with experience in both the software and hardware side of the tech industry as well as the medical field. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys backpacking, mountain biking and camping in the mountains of Colorado. Interested in gaining new and interesting experiences in the field of Computer Science.

# Work Experience

#### **CSU - Natural User Interaction Lab**

Fort Collins CO

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Currently working as a research assistant with CSU's NUILab

May. 2020 - Present

IOS Development

Denver CO

IOS DEVELOPER FOR DCSO AND MAYO CLINIC

July. 2019 - Present

- Currently working with Mayo clinic to design a custom vaccine App for patient care
- · Designed using SwiftUI
- Wrote custom IOS Application for Douglas County Sheriffs Office
- Designed and Created a secure back-end using AWS Lambda and API Gateway

### **Valor Christian High School**

Highlands Ranch, CO. Aug. 2016 - May. 2018

IT INTERN

- Provided hardware and software solutions for help desk tickets
- Helped manage a JAMF environment of 550 Apple devices
- Setup and management of 20 Aerohive network access points

#### **Express Care**

Cheyenne, WY

May. 2016 - Jul. 2016

MEDICAL ASSISTANT

- Assisted Doctor or PA on call as a scribe
- Vitals and initial patient charts
- · Strep, urine and vision tests

## Education

## COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY(COLLEGE OF NATURAL SCIENCES)

Fort Collins, CO

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

- Relevant Coursework:
- Intro to Java Programming (Java), Data Structures (Java), Computer Organization (C/C++), OS and Networks (Bash)
- Discrete Structures and their Applications (Python), Managing Big Data (Python)

## **Valor Christian High School**

Highlands Ranch, CO

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Aug. 2014 - May. 2018

• Relevant Coursework: AP Computer Science (Java)

#### Other\_

### HackCU VI winner Boulder, CO

!BACKENE

Feb 22-23

- Wrote angular front end for an easy to use API creation tool.
- Won fourth place overall in the competition. Details: https://devpost.com/software/backend-rzdbu3

# Extracurricular Activity

### **Skills & Talents**

PERSONAL

- · Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Bash, Swift
- · Software: OSX, Windows, Linux, AWS, Xcode, Personal Website, Unity

### **Eagle Scout - Troop 102**

Greenwood Village, CO

PATROL LEADER, TROOP HISTORIAN

Sep. 2011 - May. 2015

Aug. 2017

- Learned Leadership and organization through positions of patrol leader and troop historian
- · Project: Build garden and fence around local monastery

Medical Missions Work Ethiopia

MEDICAL ASSISTANT

- Assisted physicians with scribe work and basic medical tests.
- · Video: https://govalor.com/discovery-ethiopia-video/